MANJUNATH KUMAR

Web Developer

SUMMARY

Performance-driven and knowledgeable app developer with experience in improving performance, testing and updating the existing websites and developing new websites functionalities. Highly motivated individual and a solid product developer with a strong interest in solving business problems using a modern technology stack. My various technology and skills while making a significant contribution to the success of your organization.

Skills



Professional Experience

01/2021 - 10/2021

Software Engineer

Hype Luxury India, Bengaluru

- The front-end use HTML5, CSS3, Vue JS, React JS and Bootstrap to build a single page web app that communicates with the back-end via RESTful API.
- The back-end use of Node JS, Express JS, MongoDB and Mongoose, the complete MERN Stack to provide RESTful API.
- Very proficient knowledge of JIRA to track issues and communicate with other teams in various environments.
- Daily programming in server-side by using Node.JS, Firebase Cloud Function, Express JS.
- Used Git version control and Interacted with Testing Team and Business Analysts for Fixing the Issues

09/2020 - 01/2021

Junior Developer

Qliclabs Technologies, Mangalore

- Using C# for frontend development and Php Codeigniter framework for the backend development.
- Built APIs to retrieve Product Information from Aws server.
- Tested Restful APIs using Postman Tool.
- The collaborative experience of building projects on Git & Github.
- Managed effective interaction and teamwork with internal teams for deliverables.
- Develop the Desktop Applications.

12/2019 - 06/2020

Full Stack Developer Intern

MicroDegree Technologies India, Mangaluru

- Using Reactjs library developed GitHub finder and contact keeper project
- Built APis to retrieve User Information from Nodejs Server
- Tested Restful APIs using Postman Tool
- Created tables in MongoDb and used CRUD Operations to work on user data
- Created authentication leveraging Expressis
- Developed contact keeper project using MERN stack
- The collaborative experience of building projects on Git & Github
- Managed effective interaction and teamwork with internal teams for deliverables

Education

2018 – 2020	Master of Computer Application (2020), Nitte Mahalinga Adyanthaya Memorial Institute of Technology, Nitte	7.86 CGPA
2015 – 2018	Bachelor of computer application (2018), Sri Bhuvanendra College, Karkala	68%